- id: k-joyo-5f15
  prompt: "Meanings: pull, tug, jerk\nOnyomi: イン\nKunyomi: ひ.く, ひ.ける"
  answers:
    - 引
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7fbd
  prompt: "Meanings: feathers, counter for birds, rabbits\nOnyomi: ウ\nKunyomi: は, わ, はね"
  answers:
    - 羽
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-96f2
  prompt: "Meanings: cloud\nOnyomi: ウン\nKunyomi: くも, -ぐも"
  answers:
    - 雲
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5712
  prompt: "Meanings: park, garden, yard\nOnyomi: エン\nKunyomi: その"
  answers:
    - 園
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9060
  prompt: "Meanings: distant, far\nOnyomi: エン, オン\nKunyomi: とお.い"
  answers:
    - 遠
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4f55
  prompt: "Meanings: what\nOnyomi: カ\nKunyomi: なに, なん, なに-, なん-"
  answers:
    - 何
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-79d1
  prompt: "Meanings: department, course, section\nOnyomi: カ"
  answers:
    - 科
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-590f
  prompt: "Meanings: summer\nOnyomi: カ, ガ, ゲ\nKunyomi: なつ"
  answers:
    - 夏
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5bb6
  prompt: "Meanings: house, home, family\nOnyomi: カ, ケ\nKunyomi: いえ, や, うち"
  answers:
    - 家
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6b4c
  prompt: "Meanings: song, sing\nOnyomi: カ\nKunyomi: うた, うた.う"
  answers:
    - 歌
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-753b
  prompt: "Meanings: brush-stroke, picture\nOnyomi: ガ, カク, エ, カイ\nKunyomi: えが.く, かく.する, かぎ.る, はかりごと"
  answers:
    - 画
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-56de
  prompt: "Meanings: -times, round, game\nOnyomi: カイ, エ\nKunyomi: まわ.る, -まわ.る, -まわ.り, まわ.す"
  answers:
    - 回
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4f1a
  prompt: "Meanings: meeting, meet, party\nOnyomi: カイ, エ\nKunyomi: あ.う, あ.わせる, あつ.まる"
  answers:
    - 会
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6d77
  prompt: "Meanings: sea, ocean\nOnyomi: カイ\nKunyomi: うみ"
  answers:
    - 海
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7d75
  prompt: "Meanings: picture, drawing, painting\nOnyomi: カイ, エ"
  answers:
    - 絵
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5916
  prompt: "Meanings: outside\nOnyomi: ガイ, ゲ\nKunyomi: そと, ほか, はず.す, はず.れる"
  answers:
    - 外
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-89d2
  prompt: "Meanings: angle, corner, square\nOnyomi: カク\nKunyomi: かど, つの"
  answers:
    - 角
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-697d
  prompt: "Meanings: music, comfort, ease\nOnyomi: ガク, ラク, ゴウ\nKunyomi: たの.しい, たの.しむ, この.む"
  answers:
    - 楽
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6d3b
  prompt: "Meanings: lively, resuscitation, being helped\nOnyomi: カツ\nKunyomi: い.きる, い.かす, い.ける"
  answers:
    - 活
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9593
  prompt: "Meanings: interval, space\nOnyomi: カン, ケン\nKunyomi: あいだ, ま, あい"
  answers:
    - 間
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4e38
  prompt: "Meanings: round, full (month), perfection\nOnyomi: ガン\nKunyomi: まる, まる.める, まる.い"
  answers:
    - 丸
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5ca9
  prompt: "Meanings: boulder, rock, cliff\nOnyomi: ガン\nKunyomi: いわ"
  answers:
    - 岩
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9854
  prompt: "Meanings: face, expression\nOnyomi: ガン\nKunyomi: かお"
  answers:
    - 顔
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6c7d
  prompt: "Meanings: vapor, steam\nOnyomi: キ"
  answers:
    - 汽
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8a18
  prompt: "Meanings: scribe, account, narrative\nOnyomi: キ\nKunyomi: しる.す"
  answers:
    - 記
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5e30
  prompt: "Meanings: homecoming, arrive at, lead to\nOnyomi: キ\nKunyomi: かえ.る, かえ.す, おく.る, とつ.ぐ"
  answers:
    - 帰
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5f13
  prompt: "Meanings: bow, bow (archery, violin)\nOnyomi: キュウ\nKunyomi: ゆみ"
  answers:
    - 弓
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-725b
  prompt: "Meanings: cow\nOnyomi: ギュウ\nKunyomi: うし"
  answers:
    - 牛
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9b5a
  prompt: "Meanings: fish\nOnyomi: ギョ\nKunyomi: うお, さかな, -ざかな"
  answers:
    - 魚
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4eac
  prompt: "Meanings: capital, 10**16\nOnyomi: キョウ, ケイ, キン\nKunyomi: みやこ"
  answers:
    - 京
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5f37
  prompt: "Meanings: strong\nOnyomi: キョウ, ゴウ\nKunyomi: つよ.い, つよ.まる, つよ.める, し.いる"
  answers:
    - 強
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6559
  prompt: "Meanings: teach, faith, doctrine\nOnyomi: キョウ\nKunyomi: おし.える, おそ.わる"
  answers:
    - 教
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8fd1
  prompt: "Meanings: near, early, akin\nOnyomi: キン, コン\nKunyomi: ちか.い"
  answers:
    - 近
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5144
  prompt: "Meanings: elder brother, big brother\nOnyomi: ケイ, キョウ\nKunyomi: あに"
  answers:
    - 兄
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5f62
  prompt: "Meanings: shape, form, style\nOnyomi: ケイ, ギョウ\nKunyomi: かた, -がた, かたち, なり"
  answers:
    - 形
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8a08
  prompt: "Meanings: plot, plan, scheme\nOnyomi: ケイ\nKunyomi: はか.る, はか.らう"
  answers:
    - 計
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5143
  prompt: "Meanings: beginning, former time, origin\nOnyomi: ゲン, ガン\nKunyomi: もと"
  answers:
    - 元
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8a00
  prompt: "Meanings: say, word\nOnyomi: ゲン, ゴン\nKunyomi: い.う, こと"
  answers:
    - 言
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-539f
  prompt: "Meanings: meadow, original, primitive\nOnyomi: ゲン\nKunyomi: はら"
  answers:
    - 原
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6238
  prompt: "Meanings: door, counter for houses, door radical (no. 63)\nOnyomi: コ\nKunyomi: と"
  answers:
    - 戸
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-53e4
  prompt: "Meanings: old\nOnyomi: コ\nKunyomi: ふる.い, ふる-, -ふる.す"
  answers:
    - 古
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5348
  prompt: "Meanings: noon, sign of the horse, 11AM-1PM\nOnyomi: ゴ\nKunyomi: うま"
  answers:
    - 午
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5f8c
  prompt: "Meanings: behind, back, later\nOnyomi: ゴ, コウ\nKunyomi: のち, うし.ろ, うしろ, あと"
  answers:
    - 後
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8a9e
  prompt: "Meanings: word, speech, language\nOnyomi: ゴ\nKunyomi: かた.る, かた.らう"
  answers:
    - 語
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5de5
  prompt: "Meanings: craft, construction, katakana e radical (no. 48)\nOnyomi: コウ, ク, グ"
  answers:
    - 工
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-516c
  prompt: "Meanings: public, prince, official\nOnyomi: コウ, ク\nKunyomi: おおやけ"
  answers:
    - 公
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5e83
  prompt: "Meanings: wide, broad, spacious\nOnyomi: コウ\nKunyomi: ひろ.い, ひろ.まる, ひろ.める, ひろ.がる"
  answers:
    - 広
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4ea4
  prompt: "Meanings: mingle, mixing, association\nOnyomi: コウ\nKunyomi: まじ.わる, まじ.える, ま.じる, まじ.る"
  answers:
    - 交
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5149
  prompt: "Meanings: ray, light\nOnyomi: コウ\nKunyomi: ひか.る, ひかり"
  answers:
    - 光
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8003
  prompt: "Meanings: consider, think over\nOnyomi: コウ\nKunyomi: かんが.える, かんが.え"
  answers:
    - 考
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-884c
  prompt: "Meanings: going, journey, carry out\nOnyomi: コウ, ギョウ, アン\nKunyomi: い.く, ゆ.く, -ゆ.き, -ゆき"
  answers:
    - 行
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9ad8
  prompt: "Meanings: tall, high, expensive\nOnyomi: コウ\nKunyomi: たか.い, たか, -だか, たか.まる"
  answers:
    - 高
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9ec4
  prompt: "Meanings: yellow\nOnyomi: コウ, オウ\nKunyomi: き, こ-"
  answers:
    - 黄
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5408
  prompt: "Meanings: fit, suit, join\nOnyomi: ゴウ, ガッ, カッ\nKunyomi: あ.う, -あ.う, あ.い, あい-"
  answers:
    - 合
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8c37
  prompt: "Meanings: valley\nOnyomi: コク\nKunyomi: たに, きわ.まる"
  answers:
    - 谷
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-56fd
  prompt: "Meanings: country\nOnyomi: コク\nKunyomi: くに"
  answers:
    - 国
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9ed2
  prompt: "Meanings: black\nOnyomi: コク\nKunyomi: くろ, くろ.ずむ, くろ.い"
  answers:
    - 黒
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4eca
  prompt: "Meanings: now\nOnyomi: コン, キン\nKunyomi: いま"
  answers:
    - 今
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-624d
  prompt: "Meanings: genius, years old, cubic shaku\nOnyomi: サイ"
  answers:
    - 才
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7d30
  prompt: "Meanings: dainty, get thin, taper\nOnyomi: サイ\nKunyomi: ほそ.い, ほそ.る, こま.か, こま.かい"
  answers:
    - 細
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4f5c
  prompt: "Meanings: make, production, prepare\nOnyomi: サク, サ\nKunyomi: つく.る, つく.り, -づく.り"
  answers:
    - 作
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7b97
  prompt: "Meanings: calculate, divining, number\nOnyomi: サン\nKunyomi: そろ"
  answers:
    - 算
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6b62
  prompt: "Meanings: stop, halt\nOnyomi: シ\nKunyomi: と.まる, -ど.まり, と.める, -と.める"
  answers:
    - 止
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5e02
  prompt: "Meanings: market, city, town\nOnyomi: シ\nKunyomi: いち"
  answers:
    - 市
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-77e2
  prompt: "Meanings: dart, arrow\nOnyomi: シ\nKunyomi: や"
  answers:
    - 矢
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-59c9
  prompt: "Meanings: elder sister\nOnyomi: シ\nKunyomi: あね, はは"
  answers:
    - 姉
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-601d
  prompt: "Meanings: think\nOnyomi: シ\nKunyomi: おも.う, おもえら.く, おぼ.す"
  answers:
    - 思
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7d19
  prompt: "Meanings: paper\nOnyomi: シ\nKunyomi: かみ"
  answers:
    - 紙
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5bfa
  prompt: "Meanings: Buddhist temple\nOnyomi: ジ\nKunyomi: てら"
  answers:
    - 寺
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-81ea
  prompt: "Meanings: oneself\nOnyomi: ジ, シ\nKunyomi: みずか.ら, おの.ずから, おの.ずと"
  answers:
    - 自
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6642
  prompt: "Meanings: time, hour\nOnyomi: ジ\nKunyomi: とき, -どき"
  answers:
    - 時
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5ba4
  prompt: "Meanings: room, apartment, chamber\nOnyomi: シツ\nKunyomi: むろ"
  answers:
    - 室
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-793e
  prompt: "Meanings: company, firm, office\nOnyomi: シャ\nKunyomi: やしろ"
  answers:
    - 社
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5f31
  prompt: "Meanings: weak, frail\nOnyomi: ジャク\nKunyomi: よわ.い, よわ.る, よわ.まる, よわ.める"
  answers:
    - 弱
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9996
  prompt: "Meanings: neck, counter for songs and poems\nOnyomi: シュ\nKunyomi: くび"
  answers:
    - 首
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-79cb
  prompt: "Meanings: autumn\nOnyomi: シュウ\nKunyomi: あき, とき"
  answers:
    - 秋
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9031
  prompt: "Meanings: week\nOnyomi: シュウ"
  answers:
    - 週
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6625
  prompt: "Meanings: springtime, spring (season)\nOnyomi: シュン\nKunyomi: はる"
  answers:
    - 春
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-66f8
  prompt: "Meanings: write\nOnyomi: ショ\nKunyomi: か.く, -が.き, -がき"
  answers:
    - 書
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5c11
  prompt: "Meanings: few, little\nOnyomi: ショウ\nKunyomi: すく.ない, すこ.し"
  answers:
    - 少
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5834
  prompt: "Meanings: location, place\nOnyomi: ジョウ, チョウ\nKunyomi: ば"
  answers:
    - 場
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8272
  prompt: "Meanings: color\nOnyomi: ショク, シキ\nKunyomi: いろ"
  answers:
    - 色
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-98df
  prompt: "Meanings: eat, food\nOnyomi: ショク, ジキ\nKunyomi: く.う, く.らう, た.べる, は.む"
  answers:
    - 食
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5fc3
  prompt: "Meanings: heart, mind, spirit\nOnyomi: シン\nKunyomi: こころ, -ごころ"
  answers:
    - 心
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-65b0
  prompt: "Meanings: new\nOnyomi: シン\nKunyomi: あたら.しい, あら.た, あら-, にい-"
  answers:
    - 新
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-89aa
  prompt: "Meanings: parent, intimacy, relative\nOnyomi: シン\nKunyomi: おや, おや-, した.しい, した.しむ"
  answers:
    - 親
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-56f3
  prompt: "Meanings: map, drawing, plan\nOnyomi: ズ, ト\nKunyomi: え, はか.る"
  answers:
    - 図
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6570
  prompt: "Meanings: number, strength, fate\nOnyomi: スウ, ス, サク, ソク\nKunyomi: かず, かぞ.える, しばしば, せ.める"
  answers:
    - 数
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-897f
  prompt: "Meanings: west, Spain\nOnyomi: セイ, サイ, ス\nKunyomi: にし"
  answers:
    - 西
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-58f0
  prompt: "Meanings: voice\nOnyomi: セイ, ショウ\nKunyomi: こえ, こわ-"
  answers:
    - 声
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-661f
  prompt: "Meanings: star, spot, dot\nOnyomi: セイ, ショウ\nKunyomi: ほし, -ぼし"
  answers:
    - 星
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6674
  prompt: "Meanings: clear up\nOnyomi: セイ\nKunyomi: は.れる, は.れ, は.れ-, -ば.れ"
  answers:
    - 晴
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5207
  prompt: "Meanings: cut, cutoff, be sharp\nOnyomi: セツ, サイ\nKunyomi: き.る, -き.る, き.り, -き.り"
  answers:
    - 切
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-96ea
  prompt: "Meanings: snow\nOnyomi: セツ\nKunyomi: ゆき"
  answers:
    - 雪
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8239
  prompt: "Meanings: ship, boat\nOnyomi: セン\nKunyomi: ふね, ふな-"
  answers:
    - 船
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7dda
  prompt: "Meanings: line, track\nOnyomi: セン\nKunyomi: すじ"
  answers:
    - 線
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-524d
  prompt: "Meanings: in front, before\nOnyomi: ゼン\nKunyomi: まえ, -まえ"
  answers:
    - 前
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7d44
  prompt: "Meanings: association, braid, plait\nOnyomi: ソ\nKunyomi: く.む, くみ, -ぐみ"
  answers:
    - 組
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8d70
  prompt: "Meanings: run\nOnyomi: ソウ\nKunyomi: はし.る"
  answers:
    - 走
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-591a
  prompt: "Meanings: many, frequent, much\nOnyomi: タ\nKunyomi: おお.い, まさ.に, まさ.る"
  answers:
    - 多
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-592a
  prompt: "Meanings: plump, thick, big around\nOnyomi: タイ, タ\nKunyomi: ふと.い, ふと.る"
  answers:
    - 太
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4f53
  prompt: "Meanings: body, substance, object\nOnyomi: タイ, テイ\nKunyomi: からだ, かたち"
  answers:
    - 体
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-53f0
  prompt: "Meanings: pedestal, a stand, counter for machines and vehicles\nOnyomi: ダイ, タイ\nKunyomi: うてな, われ, つかさ"
  answers:
    - 台
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5730
  prompt: "Meanings: ground, earth\nOnyomi: チ, ジ"
  answers:
    - 地
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6c60
  prompt: "Meanings: pond, cistern, pool\nOnyomi: チ\nKunyomi: いけ"
  answers:
    - 池
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-77e5
  prompt: "Meanings: know, wisdom\nOnyomi: チ\nKunyomi: し.る, し.らせる"
  answers:
    - 知
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8336
  prompt: "Meanings: tea\nOnyomi: チャ, サ"
  answers:
    - 茶
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-663c
  prompt: "Meanings: daytime, noon\nOnyomi: チュウ\nKunyomi: ひる"
  answers:
    - 昼
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9577
  prompt: "Meanings: long, leader, superior\nOnyomi: チョウ\nKunyomi: なが.い, おさ"
  answers:
    - 長
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9ce5
  prompt: "Meanings: bird, chicken\nOnyomi: チョウ\nKunyomi: とり"
  answers:
    - 鳥
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-671d
  prompt: "Meanings: morning, dynasty, regime\nOnyomi: チョウ\nKunyomi: あさ"
  answers:
    - 朝
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-76f4
  prompt: "Meanings: straightaway, honesty, frankness\nOnyomi: チョク, ジキ, ジカ\nKunyomi: ただ.ちに, なお.す, -なお.す, なお.る"
  answers:
    - 直
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-901a
  prompt: "Meanings: traffic, pass through, avenue\nOnyomi: ツウ, ツ\nKunyomi: とお.る, とお.り, -とお.り, -どお.り"
  answers:
    - 通
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5f1f
  prompt: "Meanings: younger brother, faithful service to elders\nOnyomi: テイ, ダイ, デ\nKunyomi: おとうと"
  answers:
    - 弟
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5e97
  prompt: "Meanings: store, shop\nOnyomi: テン\nKunyomi: みせ, たな"
  answers:
    - 店
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-70b9
  prompt: "Meanings: spot, point, mark\nOnyomi: テン\nKunyomi: つ.ける, つ.く, た.てる, さ.す"
  answers:
    - 点
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-96fb
  prompt: "Meanings: electricity\nOnyomi: デン"
  answers:
    - 電
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5200
  prompt: "Meanings: sword, saber, knife\nOnyomi: トウ\nKunyomi: かたな, そり"
  answers:
    - 刀
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-51ac
  prompt: "Meanings: winter\nOnyomi: トウ\nKunyomi: ふゆ"
  answers:
    - 冬
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5f53
  prompt: "Meanings: hit, right, appropriate\nOnyomi: トウ\nKunyomi: あ.たる, あ.たり, あ.てる, あ.て"
  answers:
    - 当
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6771
  prompt: "Meanings: east\nOnyomi: トウ\nKunyomi: ひがし"
  answers:
    - 東
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7b54
  prompt: "Meanings: solution, answer\nOnyomi: トウ\nKunyomi: こた.える, こた.え"
  answers:
    - 答
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-982d
  prompt: "Meanings: head, counter for large animals\nOnyomi: トウ, ズ, ト\nKunyomi: あたま, かしら, -がしら, かぶり"
  answers:
    - 頭
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-540c
  prompt: "Meanings: same, agree, equal\nOnyomi: ドウ\nKunyomi: おな.じ"
  answers:
    - 同
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9053
  prompt: "Meanings: road-way, street, district\nOnyomi: ドウ, トウ\nKunyomi: みち, いう"
  answers:
    - 道
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8aad
  prompt: "Meanings: read\nOnyomi: ドク, トク, トウ\nKunyomi: よ.む, -よ.み"
  answers:
    - 読
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5185
  prompt: "Meanings: inside, within, between\nOnyomi: ナイ, ダイ\nKunyomi: うち"
  answers:
    - 内
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5357
  prompt: "Meanings: south\nOnyomi: ナン, ナ\nKunyomi: みなみ"
  answers:
    - 南
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8089
  prompt: "Meanings: meat\nOnyomi: ニク\nKunyomi: しし"
  answers:
    - 肉
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-99ac
  prompt: "Meanings: horse\nOnyomi: バ\nKunyomi: うま, うま-, ま"
  answers:
    - 馬
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-58f2
  prompt: "Meanings: sell\nOnyomi: バイ\nKunyomi: う.る, う.れる"
  answers:
    - 売
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8cb7
  prompt: "Meanings: buy\nOnyomi: バイ\nKunyomi: か.う"
  answers:
    - 買
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9ea6
  prompt: "Meanings: barley, wheat\nOnyomi: バク\nKunyomi: むぎ"
  answers:
    - 麦
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-534a
  prompt: "Meanings: half, middle, odd number\nOnyomi: ハン\nKunyomi: なか.ば"
  answers:
    - 半
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-756a
  prompt: "Meanings: turn, number in a series\nOnyomi: バン\nKunyomi: つが.い"
  answers:
    - 番
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7236
  prompt: "Meanings: father\nOnyomi: フ\nKunyomi: ちち"
  answers:
    - 父
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-98a8
  prompt: "Meanings: wind, air, style\nOnyomi: フウ, フ\nKunyomi: かぜ, かざ-"
  answers:
    - 風
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5206
  prompt: "Meanings: part, minute of time, segment\nOnyomi: ブン, フン, ブ\nKunyomi: わ.ける, わ.け, わ.かれる, わ.かる"
  answers:
    - 分
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-805e
  prompt: "Meanings: hear, ask, listen\nOnyomi: ブン, モン\nKunyomi: き.く, き.こえる"
  answers:
    - 聞
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7c73
  prompt: "Meanings: rice, USA, metre\nOnyomi: ベイ, マイ, メエトル\nKunyomi: こめ, よね"
  answers:
    - 米
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6b69
  prompt: "Meanings: walk, counter for steps\nOnyomi: ホ, ブ, フ\nKunyomi: ある.く, あゆ.む"
  answers:
    - 歩
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6bcd
  prompt: "Meanings: mother\nOnyomi: ボ\nKunyomi: はは, も"
  answers:
    - 母
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-65b9
  prompt: "Meanings: direction, person, alternative\nOnyomi: ホウ\nKunyomi: かた, -かた, -がた"
  answers:
    - 方
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-5317
  prompt: "Meanings: north\nOnyomi: ホク\nKunyomi: きた"
  answers:
    - 北
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6bce
  prompt: "Meanings: every\nOnyomi: マイ\nKunyomi: ごと, -ごと.に"
  answers:
    - 毎
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-59b9
  prompt: "Meanings: younger sister\nOnyomi: マイ\nKunyomi: いもうと"
  answers:
    - 妹
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-4e07
  prompt: "Meanings: ten thousand, 10,000\nOnyomi: マン, バン\nKunyomi: よろず"
  answers:
    - 万
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-660e
  prompt: "Meanings: bright, light\nOnyomi: メイ, ミョウ, ミン\nKunyomi: あ.かり, あか.るい, あか.るむ, あか.らむ"
  answers:
    - 明
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9cf4
  prompt: "Meanings: chirp, cry, bark\nOnyomi: メイ\nKunyomi: な.く, な.る, な.らす"
  answers:
    - 鳴
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6bdb
  prompt: "Meanings: fur, hair, feather\nOnyomi: モウ\nKunyomi: け"
  answers:
    - 毛
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-9580
  prompt: "Meanings: gate, counter for cannons\nOnyomi: モン\nKunyomi: かど, と"
  answers:
    - 門
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-591c
  prompt: "Meanings: night, evening\nOnyomi: ヤ\nKunyomi: よ, よる"
  answers:
    - 夜
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-91ce
  prompt: "Meanings: plains, field, rustic\nOnyomi: ヤ, ショ\nKunyomi: の, の-"
  answers:
    - 野
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-53cb
  prompt: "Meanings: friend\nOnyomi: ユウ\nKunyomi: とも"
  answers:
    - 友
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7528
  prompt: "Meanings: utilize, business, service\nOnyomi: ヨウ\nKunyomi: もち.いる"
  answers:
    - 用
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-66dc
  prompt: "Meanings: weekday\nOnyomi: ヨウ"
  answers:
    - 曜
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-6765
  prompt: "Meanings: come, due, next\nOnyomi: ライ, タイ\nKunyomi: く.る, きた.る, きた.す, き.たす"
  answers:
    - 来
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-91cc
  prompt: "Meanings: ri, village, parent's home\nOnyomi: リ\nKunyomi: さと"
  answers:
    - 里
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-7406
  prompt: "Meanings: logic, arrangement, reason\nOnyomi: リ\nKunyomi: ことわり"
  answers:
    - 理
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []

- id: k-joyo-8a71
  prompt: "Meanings: tale, talk\nOnyomi: ワ\nKunyomi: はな.す, はなし"
  answers:
    - 話
  hint: ""
  stage: -1
  unlocks: '9999-12-31T23:59:59+00:00'
  befuddlers: []
